

SUMMARY

Versatile, personable media professional prepared to transfer effective analytical and steadfast troubleshooting skills as well as a swift capacity to learn new technologies honed during 22 years as a Production Assistant and Broadcast Technician to a career as a Software Developer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Coding: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, GitHub
- Video Editing: Beta, DVCPRO, SSD, XDCAM, Blu-ray, Avid Media Composer, Final Cut Pro, Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe Media Encoder, DaVinci Resolve, iMovie
- Software Installations: Windows, macOS, ChromeOS, Linux, Android, iOS, Router, Modem, Printer/Scanner/Copier,
 IP Camera, Laptop Screen
- Hardware Upgrades: RAM, Hard Drive, Solid State Drive, Power Supply, DC-In Board, Optical Drive, Bluetooth/Wi-Fi Card
- Miscellaneous: Bug Fixes, Data Recovery, Malware Removal, Hard Drive Cloning, Cell Phone Rooting/Jailbreaking

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KVUE TV - ABC, AUSTIN, TX

STUDIO FLOOR MANAGER, AUGUST 2022 — PRESENT

- Oversee activity on the studio floor during newscasts to support smooth broadcasts.
- Direct the movement and positioning of on-camera talent to ensure proper placement in alignment with planned broadcast times.
- Prepare floor setups for routine and special edition broadcasts.
- Collaborate with other media staff to supervise floor activity, providing assistance with tasks as needed.
- Support broadcasting operations to maintain adherence to timelines and minimize interruptions.

KVUE TV - ABC, AUSTIN, TX

BROADCAST TECHNICIAN/MASTER CONTROL OPERATOR, MAY 2012 — AUGUST 2021

- Monitored and controlled on-air programming for all station-owned channels to ensure quality and accuracy of all broadcasts.
- · Operated multiviewer systems, equipment banks, and control panels to direct live broadcasts.
- Certified adherence of all broadcast content to established government guidelines.
- Controlled and dynamically adjusted incoming and outgoing broadcast signals utilizing switchers or automation to regulate sound volume as well as signal strength and clarity.
- Identified and rapidly troubleshot malfunctions during broadcasts to minimize interruptions.
- Documented malfunctions by submitting reports and logs, following up on issues as needed.
- Demonstrated an in-depth understanding of satellite, microwave, and other transmitter equipment to effectively broadcast television programs.
- Outperformed expectations, receiving recognition as Production Employee of the Year in 2013.
- Aligned objectives and bridged communications between media providers, sales, traffic, and marketing teams to secure scheduled playback, acquire, then input commercials and shows to the sever.
- Organized the execution of short recorded news segments.
- Recorded, encoded, and edited daily promotional teases in preparation for broadcasts.
- Managed activities on the studio floor by directing on- and off-camera staff to necessary positioning.
- Reported department maintenance issues to ensure timely resolutions.
- Curated quality broadcasts by displaying chyron show graphics, controlling manual and robotic cameras, commanding the audio board, and operating the teleprompter to provide lines.

MML Page 2

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

KEYE TV – CBS, AUSTIN, TX, OCTOBER 2011 — MAY 2012 | VIDEO EDITOR

ROYAL CARIBBEAN INTERNATIONAL, CAPE CANAVERAL, FL, JULY 2011 — SEPTEMBER 2011 | BROADCAST TECHNICIAN

KOKH – FOX 25 News, Oklahoma City, OK, March 2007 — July 2011 | AUDIO OPERATOR/VIDEO EDITOR

KAUZ - CBS News Channel 6, Wichita Falls, TX, June 2004 — February 2007 | PRODUCTION ASSISTANT

KFDX - NBC TV-3, WICHITA FALLS, TX, JULY 2000 — APRIL 2004 | PRODUCTION ASSISTANT

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ARTS (B.A.) IN ART, 2005
Midwestern State University, Wichita Falls, TX

CERTIFICATES

FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT, 2023 SheCodes.io